Guide to the Asa and Elna Spaulding Papers, 1909-1997 and undated, bulk 1935-1983 RL.01240
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Elna Spaulding Subgroup, 1909-1997 and undated, bulk 1970s-1983, 34 boxes
  - Subject Files Series, 1909-1997 and undated, bulk 1974-1982, 3 boxes
    - Calendars, Appointments, and Contacts, 1976-1982 (Box ES-1, Folder 5)
    - Campaign for County Commissioner, 1974 (Box ES-1, Folder 6)
    - Campaign for County Commissioner, 1974 (Box ES-1, Folder 7)
    - Campaign for County Commissioner, 1976 (Box ES-2, Folder 1)
    - Campaign for County Commissioner, 1978 (Box ES-2, Folder 2)
    - Campaign for County Commissioner, 1980 (Box ES-2, Folder 3)
    - Campaign for County Commissioner, 1980 (Box ES-2, Folder 4)
    - Campaign for County Commissioner, 1982 (Box ES-2, Folder 5)
    - Campaign issues, 1974-1982 and undated (Box ES-3, Folder 1)
    - Campaign material, 1974-1982 and undated (Box ES-3, Folder 2)
    - Campaign material, 1974-1982 and undated (Box ES-3, Folder 3)
    - Campaign material, 1974-1982 and undated (Box ES-4, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1970-1997 (Box ES-3, Folder 5)
    - Property Tax Records, Alabama, 1978-1980 (Box ES-3, Folder 6)
    - Writings: miscellaneous notes and memoranda, 1979-1980 and undated (Box ES-3, Folder 7)
    - Writings: miscellaneous notes and memoranda, 1979-1980 and undated (Box ES-3, Folder 8)
    - Writings: speeches and statements, 1978-1981 and undated (Box ES-3, Folder 9)
  - Photographic Materials Series, undated
    Photographs documenting Elna Spaulding's political career. Arranged by topic corresponding to related materials in the Organizations Series.
    - Durham County Board of Commissioners, undated (Box APM-4, Folder 1)
      Photographs of one of Elna Spaulding's swearing-in ceremonies.
  - Audiovisual Materials Series (Original Copies), 1980 and undated
    Audiotapes documenting Elna Spaulding's campaigns for Durham County Commissioner. Related campaign material also appears in the Subject Files Series.
    [Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.]
    - OR26. Committee to Re-elect Elna B. Spaulding (Durham County Commissioner), WPTF Radio 68, 1980 Apr. 17 (:30) (Box AV-4, Folder 1)
    - OR27. Elna B. Spaulding, 1 (30) sec. political advertisement, WDUR 1490, undated (Box AV-4, Folder 2)
    - OR28. Elna B. Spaulding for County Commissioner, undated (Box AV-4, Folder 3)
    - OR29. Sound Truck--Inspiration for Voters, 1968 (Box AV-4, Folder 4)
      Short (less than one minute) recordings by various speakers, including Julian Bond and Jackie Robinson. Voter registration drive in Mississippi, campaign for Hubert Humphrey and Edmund Muskie in 1968 presidential race.
  - Oversize Materials,1932 and undated
    Printed material documenting Elna Spaulding's private life and political career. Arranged alphabetically by topics corresponding to related materials in the Subject Files Series.
    - Biographical data: certificate from National Academy of Music, 1932 (Box AOM-2, Folder 1)
    - Campaigns for County Commissioner: campaign poster, undated (Box AOM-2, Folder 2)
- Spaulding Family Subgroup, 1933-1982; 1
  Scope and Contents
  The Spaulding Family Subgroup includes information about Spauldings beyond Asa and Elna Spaulding. It includes Family Genealogy, Aaron L. Spaulding, and a Name Files series.
  - Family Genealogy, 1
    - Bridgeforth Family, 1933-1981 (Box SF-1)
    - Lowery, 1979 (Box SF-1)
    - Louis D. Mitchell on Family History, 1979 (Box SF-1)
    - Madeline Spaulding Blanks Mitchell Family, 1981 (Box SF-1)
    - Aaron McDuffie Moore, 1977-1980 (Box SF-1)
    - Patricia Spaulding Moore, 1959-1980 and undated (Box SF-1)
    - Spaulding Family History, 1949 (Box SF-1)
    - Spaulding Family Reunion, 1949 and 1982 (Box SF-1)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box SF-1)
  - Aaron L. Spaulding, 1938-1981; 2
    - Biographical Information, 1979-1983 and undated (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence with Patricia Spaulding Moore and Children, 1964-1983 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence with Dr. A.L. Spaulding, 1938 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence with Patricia Alford, 1964 Sept 24-1965 Mar 10 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence with Patricia Alford, 1963 Dec 23-1964 Sept 23 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence with Patricia Alford, 1965 Mar 13-1965 Nov 10 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence, A-B, 1964-1976 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence, C-D, 1964-1965 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence, E-F, 1961-1965 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence, G-H, 1964-1965 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence, I-J, 1964 (Box SF-1)
    - Correspondence, K-L, 1963-1964 (Box SF-2)
    - Correspondence, M-N, 1964-1965 (Box SF-2)
    - Correspondence, O-P, 1963-1964 (Box SF-2)
    - Correspondence, Q-R, 1964 (Box SF-2)
    - Correspondence, S-T, 1959-1970 (Box SF-2)
    - Correspondence, V-Z, 1964-1965 (Box SF-2)
    - Correspondence, Spaulding, 1964-1974 (Box SF-2)
    - Unknown, 1964-1981 (Box SF-2)
  - Spaulding Family Name Files, 1936-1983; 3
    - Andrew M. Spaulding, 1936-1939 (Box SF-2)
    - Annie Bell Lowery Spaulding, 1965 (Box SF-2)
    - Armstead Spaulding, 1975 (Box SF-2)
    - Asa T. Spaulding, Jr., 1952-1982 and undated (Box SF-2)
    - C.C. Spaulding, 1959-1982; 2 folders (Box SF-2)
    - Various Family Members, 1943-1971; 2 folders (Box SF-3)
    - Lloyd M. Spaulding, 1959-1961 (Box SF-3)
    - Hattie Spaulding, 1960-1961 (Box SF-3)
    - George Spaulding, 1959-1974 (Box SF-3)
    - Dr. Fuller Spaulding, 1979 (Box SF-3)
    - Kenneth Spaulding, 1960-1984 (Box SF-3)
      Includes Congress campaign banner from 1984.
    - Armstead Spaulding, 1936-1946 (Box SF-3)
    - Cecil Spaulding, 1960-1983 (Box SF-3)
    - Charles C. Spaulding, III, 1965 (Box SF-3)
    - John Andrew Spaulding, 1936-1938 (Box SF-3)
    - Lula Spaulding, 1981 (Box SF-3)
    - Theodore O. Spaulding, 1961-1965 (Box SF-3)
    - Mack Spaulding, 1939-1941 (Box SF-3)
    - Minnie T. Spaulding, undated (Box SF-3)
    - Spaulding Family, 1981 Mar 9 (Box SF-3)